Papers of William E. Thomas 1885-1922
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers of William E. Thomas 1885-1922
AZ 018
Thomas, William E.
Correspondence, reports, bills, legal documents, and financial records pertaining to William E. Thomas' busines and political activities in Arizona.
0.4 Linear ft
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection
Biographical Note
Businessman, city and county official, of Phoenix, Ariz. Served as Postmaster of Phoenix, 1894-1898, and of Liberty, Ariz., 1901, 1905.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 5 series
Series I: Correspondence 1896-1922
Series II: Financial records 1895-1920
Series III: Mining papers 1894-1920
Series IV: Legal records 1889-1912.
Series V: Post Office papers 1894-1905.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, reports, bills, legal documents, and financial records pertaining to Thomas' activities in real estate, mining, business, politics, and his public service as postmaster, clerk of Maricopa County Board of Supervisors and clerk of Maricopa County Superior Court. Includes mining records for various locations chiefly the Blue Bird Mine and Prince of Arizona Mining Company.
Access Terms
Mines and mineral resources--Arizona--Maricopa County.
Mines and mineral resources--Arizona--Yavapai County.
Real property--Arizona--Phoenix.
Postal service--Arizona--History--Sources.
.; Land titles--Arizona.
Prince of Arizona Mining Company.
Blue Bird Mine (Ariz.)
Arizona. Superior Court (Maricopa County)>
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence1896-1922
  - 1896-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1916-1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Financial records1885-1920
  - Bills, 1885-1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blue Bird Mine (formerly Donald Mine), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Clerk, Superior Court, Maricopa County, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - La Coronado Development Company, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General Merchandise Store, Liberty, Arizona, 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Land and Real estate papers(miscellaneous), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Legal papers: Agreements, mortgages, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series III: Mining Papers1896-1922
  - 1896-1914 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Financial papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Personal, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 13a)
- Series IV: Legal Records1889-1912
  - Prince of Arizona Mining company, 1896-1914 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stock certificates, 1881-1907 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stock certificates, 1881-1907 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Taxes (state and county), 1904-1917 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series V: U.S. Post Office Papers1889-1912
  - Phoenix, 1894-1898 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Liberty, 1901-1905 (Box 1, Folder 17)